<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  - SPDX-License-Identifier: CC0-1.0
  - SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2020-2021 Carl Schwan <carlschwan@kde.org>
  - SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2020-2021 Tobias Fella <tobias.fella@kde.org>
 -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.neochat</id>
  <provides>
    <binary>neochat</binary>
  </provides>
  <name>NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ar">نيوتشات</name>
  <name xml:lang="az">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="eu">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ia">Neochat</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ie">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="pa">ਨਿਓ-ਚੈਟ</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ta">நியோச்சாட்</name>
  <name xml:lang="tr">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxNeoChatxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">NeoChat</name>
  <summary>A client for matrix, the decentralized communication protocol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ar">عميل لماتركس، ميفاق الاتصال اللامركزي</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="az">Matrix üçün müştəri, mərkəzləşməmiş kommunikasiya protokolu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Un client de Matrix, el protocol de comunicacions descentralitzat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Un client de Matrix, el protocol de comunicacions descentralitzat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Klient pro decentralizovaný komunikační protokol matrix</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Ein Programm für Matrix, das dezentrale Kommunikationsprotokoll</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Ένας πελάτης για το Matrix, το αποκεντρωμένο πρωτόκολλο επικοινωνίας</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">A client for matrix, the decentralised communication protocol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Un cliente para Matrix, el protocolo de comunicaciones descentralizado</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Matrix, deszentralizatutako komunikazio protokolorako bezero bat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Asiakas Matrixille, hajautetulle viestintäyhteyskäytännölle</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Un client pour « Matrix », le protocole décentralisé de communications.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">Kliens a matrixhoz, a decentralizált kommunikációs protokollhoz</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ia">Un cliente per Matrix, le protocollo de communication decentralisate</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Klien untuk matrix, protokol komunikasi terdesentralisasi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ie">Un cliente de Matrix, li protocol de communication decentralisat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Un client per matrix, il protocollo di comunicazione decentralizzato</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ka">კლიენტი Matrix-სთვის, დეცენტრალიზებული კომუნიკაციის პროტოკოლისთვის</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">Matrix, 분산 대화 프로토콜 클라이언트</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Een client voor matrix, het gedecentraliseerde communicatieprotocol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Ein klient for Matrix, den desentraliserte lynmeldings­protokollen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pa">ਮੈਟਰਿਕਸ, ਸਰਬ-ਸਾਂਝੇ ਸੰਚਾਰ ਪਰੋਟੋਕਾਲ, ਲਈ ਕਲਾਈਂਟ ਹੈ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Program do obsługi matriksa, rozproszonego protokołu porozumiewania się</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Um cliente para o Matrix, o protocolo de comunicação descentralizado</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Um cliente do Matrix, o protocolo de comunicação descentralizado</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Клиент для Matrix — децентрализованного коммуникационного протокола</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Klient pre matrix, decentralizovaný komunikačný protokol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Odjemalec za matrix, decentralizirani komunikacijski protokol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">En klient för Matrix, det decentraliserade kommunikationsprotokollet</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Merkezi olmayan iletişim protokolü Matrix için bir istemci</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Клієнт matrix, децентралізованого протоколу обміну даними</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxA client for matrix, the decentralized communication protocolxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">分布式通讯协议 Matrix 的客户端</summary>
  <description>
    <p>NeoChat is a client for Matrix, the decentralized communication protocol for instant messaging. It allows you to send text messages, videos and audio files to your family, colleagues and friends. It uses KDE frameworks and most notably Kirigami
to provide a convergent experience across multiple platforms.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">نيوتشات هو عميل ماتركس Matrix، (ميفاق الاتصال اللامركزي للمراسلة الفورية). يتيح لك نيوتشات إرسال رسائل نصية ومقاطع فيديو وملفات صوتية إلى عائلتك وزملائك وأصدقائك. يستخدم أطر عمل كيدي وأبرزها Kirigami لتوفير تجربة متقاربة عبر منصات متعددة.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El NeoChat és un client de Matrix, el protocol descentralitzat de comunicacions de missatgeria instantània. Permet enviar missatges de text, fitxers de vídeo i d'àudio a la família, col·legues i amics. Fa servir els Frameworks de KDE i, sobretot, el Kirigami per a proporcionar una experiència convergent a través de diverses plataformes.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">NeoChat és un client de Matrix, el protocol descentralitzat de comunicacions de missatgeria instantània. Permet enviar missatges de text, fitxers de vídeo i d'àudio a la família, col·legues i amics. Utilitza els Frameworks de KDE i, sobretot, Kirigami per a proporcionar una experiència convergent a través de diverses plataformes.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">NeoChat es un cliente para Matrix, el protocolo de comunicaciones descentralizado para mensajería instantánea. Le permite enviar mensajes de texto, vídeos y archivos de sonido a su familia, compañeros de trabajo y amigos. Usa la infraestructura de KDE y, en particular, Kirigami para proporcionar una experiencia convergente en muchas plataformas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">NeoChat არის Matrix კლიენტი. ის საშუალებას გაძლევთ გაგზავნოთ ტექსტური შეტყობინებები, ვიდეოები და აუდიო ფაილები თქვენს ოჯახს, კოლეგებსა და მეგობრებს მატრიქსის პროტოკოლის გამოყენებით.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">NeoChat is een client voor Matrix, het gedecentraliseerde communicatieprotocol voor instant messages. Het biedt u het verzenden van tekstberichten, video's en geluidsbestanden naar uw familie, collega's en vrienden. Het gebruik KDE frameworks en het meest opmerkelijk Kirigami om een convergente ervaring te leveren op meerdere platforms.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O NeoChat é um cliente do Matrix. O mesmo permite-lhe enviar mensagens de texto, ficheiros de vídeo e áudio para a sua família, colegas e amigos com o protocolo Matrix. Usa as plataformas do KDE, e principalmente o Kirigami, para oferecer uma experiência convergente entre várias plataformas.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Neochat je odjemalec za Matrix, decentralizirani komunikacijski protokol za takojšnje sporočanje. Omogoča vam pošiljanje besedilnih sporočil, videoposnetkov in zvočnih datotek svoji družini, sodelavcem in prijateljem. Uporablja okvire ogrodje KDE frameworks in predvsem Kirigami za zagotavljanje konvergentne izkušnje na več platformah.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">NeoChat, anlık iletileşme için merkezi olmayan iletişim protokolü olan Matrix için bir istemcidir. Ailenize, iş arkadaşlarınıza ve arkadaşlarınıza metin iletiler, videolar ve ses dosyaları göndermenize olanak tanır. Birden çok platformda yakınsak bir deneyim sağlamak için KDE Frameworks ve en önemlilerinden Kirigami'yi kullanır.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">NeoChat — клієнт Matrix, децентралізованого протоколу спілкування для миттєвого обміну повідомленнями. За його допомогою ви можете надсилати текстові повідомлення, відео та звукові файли вашій родин, колегами та друзям. У програмі використано бібліотеки KDE, зокрема Kirigami, для надання однорідного середовища на декількох програмних та апаратних платформах.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxNeoChat is a client for Matrix, the decentralized communication protocol for instant messaging. It allows you to send text messages, videos and audio files to your family, colleagues and friends. It uses KDE frameworks and most notably Kirigami to provide a convergent experience across multiple platforms.xx</p>
    <p>NeoChat aims to be a fully featured application for the Matrix specification. As such everything in the current stable specification with the notable exceptions of VoIP, threads and some aspects of End-to-End Encryption are supported. There are a few other smaller omissions due to the fact that the Matrix spec is constantly evolving but the aim remains to provide eventual support for the entire spec.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">يهدف نيوتشات إلى أن يكون تطبيقًا كامل الميزات لمواصفات ماتركس. على هذا النحو يتم دعم كل شيء في المواصفات المستقرة الحالية مع الاستثناءات الملحوظة لـ VoIP والخيوط وبعض جوانب التشفير من طرف إلى طرف. هناك عدد قليل من الإغفالات الصغيرة الأخرى بسبب حقيقة أن مواصفات ماتركس تتطور باستمرار ، ولكن يبقى الهدف توفير الدعم النهائي للمواصفات بأكملها.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">NeoChat pretén ser una aplicació amb totes les característiques per a l'especificació de Matrix. Com a tal, s'ha implementat tota l'especificació actual estable amb les notables excepcions de la VoIP, fils i alguns aspectes de l'encriptatge d'extrem a extrem. Hi ha algunes altres omissions més petites a causa del fet que l'especificació de Matrix està evolucionant constantment, però l'objectiu segueix sent proporcionar suport eventual per a tota l'especificació.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">NeoChat pretén ser una aplicació amb totes les característiques per a l'especificació de Matrix. Com a tal, s'ha implementat tota l'especificació actual estable amb les notables excepcions de VoIP, fils i alguns aspectes de l'encriptació d'extrem a extrem. Hi ha algunes altres omissions més xicotetes a causa del fet que l'especificació de Matrix està evolucionant constantment, però l'objectiu seguix sent proporcionar suport eventual per a tota l'especificació.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">NeoChat pretende ser una aplicación con todas las funciones para la especificación de Matrix. Como tal, admite todo en la especificación estable actual, con las notables excepciones de VoIP, subprocesos y algunas funciones de cifrado de extremo a extremo. Existen algunas omisiones menos importantes debido al hecho de que la especificación de Matrix está en constante evolución, pero el objetivo sigue siendo brindar compatibilidad final con toda la especificación.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">NeoChat-ი მიზნად ისახავს Matrix სპეციფიკაციის სრული განხორციელება ჰქონდეს. როგორც ასეთი, ყველაფერი მიმდინარე სპეციფიკაციიდან, VoIP-ის, ძაფებისა და გამჭოლი დაშიფვრის ზოგიერთი ასპექტის გარდა, მხარდაჭერილია. შეძლება ასევე იყოს მცირე ლაფსუსებიც იმის გამო, რომ Matrix-ის სპეციფიკაცია მუდმივად ვითარგდება, მაგრამ ჩვენი მიზანი მისი სრული მხარდაჭერაა.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">NeoChat richt zich op het volledig bieden van alle mogelijkheden van de Matrix-specificatie. Alles in de huidige stabiele specificatie met merkbare uitzondering van VoIP, gekoppelde discussies en sommige aspecten van eind-tot-eind versleuteling worden ondersteund. Er zijn een paar andere kleinere omissies vanwege het feit dat de Matrix specificatie constant evolueert maar het doel blijft het eventueel bieden van ondersteuning van de gehele specificatie.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O NeoChat pretende ser uma aplicação completa para a especificação do Matrix. Como tal, tudo o que existe na especificação estável actual, com as notáveis excepções do VoIP, tópicos e alguns aspectos da Encriptação Ponto-a-Ponto, são suportados. Existem mais algumas omissões, devido ao facto que a norma do Matrix está em constante evolução, mas o objectivo continua a ser oferecer o suporte eventual para a norma por inteiro.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Neochat cilja, da bi bila popolna aplikacija po specifikaciji Matrixa. Kot takšna vsebuje vse v trenutni stabilni specifikaciji z pomembnimi izjemami pri VoIP, nitih in nekaterih vidikov šifriranja od konca do konca. Obstaja nekaj drugih manjših opustitev zaradi dejstva, da se specifikacija Matrix nenehno razvija, vendar cilj ostaja zagotoviti morebitno podporo celotni specifikaciji.</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">NeoChat, Matrix spesifikasyonu için tam özellikli bir uygulama olmayı hedefler. Bu nedenle; VoIP, ileti zincirleri ve Uçtan Uca Şifrelemenin bazı yönleri gibi dikkate değer istisnalar dışında var olan kararlı belirtimdeki her şey desteklenir. Matrix belirtiminin sürekli gelişmesi nedeniyle birkaç küçük eksiklik daha var; ancak amaç tüm belirtim için nihai destek sağlamak olmayı sürdürüyor.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Метою створення NeoChat є повноцінна реалізація програми для специфікації Matrix. Як наслідок, реалізовано усе у поточній стабільній специфікації, окрім голосового інтернет-зв'язку, потоків та деяких аспектів міжвузлового шифрування. Є також декілька інших незначних прогалин через те, що специфікація Matrix постійно змінюється, але метою лишається повна підтримка специфікації.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxNeoChat aims to be a fully featured application for the Matrix specification. As such everything in the current stable specification with the notable exceptions of VoIP, threads and some aspects of End-to-End Encryption are supported. There are a few other smaller omissions due to the fact that the Matrix spec is constantly evolving but the aim remains to provide eventual support for the entire spec.xx</p>
    <p>Due to the nature of the Matrix specification development NeoChat also supports numerous unstable features. Currently these are:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ar">نظرًا لطبيعة تطوير مواصفات ماتركس، يدعم نيوتشات أيضًا العديد من الميزات غير المستقرة وهي:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">A causa de la naturalesa del desenvolupament de l'especificació de Matrix, el NeoChat també implementa nombroses característiques inestables. Actualment són:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">A causa de la naturalea del desenvolupament de l'especificació de Matrix, NeoChat també implementa nombroses característiques inestables. Actualment són:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Debido a la naturaleza del desarrollo de la especificación de Matrix, NeoChat también permite numerosas funciones no estables, como:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">Matrix-ის სპეციფიკაციის განვითარების ბუნების გამო NeoChat-ს ასევე აქვს უამრავი არასტაბილური ფუნქციაც. ახლა ისინია:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Vanwege de aard van de ontwikkeling van de Matrix specificatie ondersteunt NeoChat ook talloze onstabiele mogelijkheden. Dit zijn nu:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Devido à natureza do desenvolvimento da especificação do Matrix, o NeoChat também suporta diversas funcionalidades instáveis. De momento são:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Zaradi narave razvoja specifikacije Matrixa NeoChat podpira tudi številne nestabilne zmožnosti. Trenutno so to:</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">NeoChat, Matrix belirtim geliştirmesinin doğası gereği çok sayıda kararsız özelliği de destekler. Şu anda bunlar:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Через природу розробки специфікації Matrix, у NeoChat також передбачено підтримку численних нестабільних можливостей. У поточній версії цими можливостями є:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxDue to the nature of the Matrix specification development NeoChat also supports numerous unstable features. Currently these are:xx</p>
    <ul>&gt;
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://apps.kde.org/neochat/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/buglist.cgi?component=General&amp;product=NeoChat</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
  </categories>
  <developer_name>The KDE Community</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ar">مجتمع كِيدِي</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="az">KDE Cəmiyyəti</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ca">La comunitat KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ca-valencia">La comunitat KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="cs">Komunita KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="de">Die KDE-Gemeinschaft</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="el">Η Κοινότητα του KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="en-GB">The KDE Community</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="es">La comunidad KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="eu">KDE komunitatea</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fi">KDE-yhteisö</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fr">La communauté de KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="hu">A KDE Közösség</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ia">Le communitate de KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="id">Komunitas KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ie">Li comunité de KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="it">La comunità KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ka">KDE-ის საზოგადოება</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ko">KDE 커뮤니티</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="nl">De KDE gemeenschap</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="nn">KDE-fellesskapet</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pa">ਕੇਡੀਈ ਕਮਿਊਨਟੀ</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pl">Społeczność KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pt">A Comunidade do KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pt-BR">A comunidade KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ru">Сообщество KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sk">KDE Komunita</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sl">Skupnost KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sv">KDE-gemenskapen</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="tr">KDE Topluluğu</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="uk">Спільнота KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="x-test">xxThe KDE Communityxx</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="zh-CN">KDE 社区</developer_name>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <custom>
    <value key="KDE::matrix">#neochat:kde.org</value>
    <value key="KDE::windows_store">https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PNXWVNRC29H</value>
  </custom>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.kde.neochat.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/neochat/application-mobile.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/neochat/application.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <releases>
    <release version="23.04.1" date="2023-05-11"/>
    <release version="23.04.0" date="2023-04-20">
      <artifacts>
        <artifact type="binary" platform="x86_64-windows-msvc">
          <location>https://download.kde.org/stable/release-service/23.04.0/windows/neochat-23.04.0-512-windows-cl-msvc2019-x86_64.exe</location>
          <checksum type="sha256">85e17fdd9b128bfdd171a93b11f7a95febeff0a00df9261df11f6ff67637686d</checksum>
          <size type="download">58032464</size>
        </artifact>
      </artifacts>
    </release>
    <release version="23.01" date="2023-01-30">
      <url>https://plasma-mobile.org/2023/01/30/january-blog-post/</url>
      <description>
        <p>New features and bugfixes:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Notifications will now be shown for all accounts, not just the active one</li>
          <li>There is a new "compact" mode for the room list</li>
          <li>You can now search in the room history</li>
          <li>Emojis and Reactions have been significantly improved</li>
          <li>Fixed several crashes around user invitations</li>
          <li>Room permission settings can now be configured</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="22.11" date="2022-11-30">
      <url>https://plasma-mobile.org/2022/11/30/plasma-mobile-gear-22-11/</url>
    </release>
    <release version="22.09" date="2022-09-27">
      <url>https://www.plasma-mobile.org/2022/09/27/plasma-mobile-gear-22-09/</url>
    </release>
    <release version="22.06" date="2022-06-24">
      <url>https://www.plasma-mobile.org/2022/06/28/plasma-mobile-gear-22-06/</url>
      <description>
        <p>This release brings you various small bugfixes and improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Sending of typing notifications can now be disabled.</li>
          <li>In the room list, the scrollbar will now disappear correctly when it is not needed.</li>
          <li>On wayland, NeoChat will now raise correctly when clicking on a notification.</li>
          <li>Several bugs have been fixed that would sometimes cause messages containing markdown and/or HTML elements to be sent incorrectly.</li>
          <li>The quick switcher can now be controlled using the mouse.</li>
          <li>There is now an option to disable automatic room sidebar opening when resizing the window.</li>
          <li>Creation of custom emojis has been fixed.</li>
          <li>Editing or replying to the last message using the keyboard shortcuts now works correctly.</li>
          <li>When switching between rooms using the keyboard, the switching direction is now correct.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="22.04" date="2022-04-26">
      <url>https://www.plasma-mobile.org/2022/04/26/plasma-mobile-gear-22-04/</url>
      <description>
        <p>NeoChat now lets you filter and enter a room directly from KRunner (Plasma Search). Aside from that there is also various bug fixes regarding the typing notifications.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="22.02" date="2022-02-09">
      <description>
        <p>NeoChat 22.02 focus on stability and adds a few quality of life improvements</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Add support for minimizing to system tray on startup</li>
          <li>Improved internet connectivity check</li>
          <li>Add support for sharing images and files with other apps (Nextcloud, Imgur, ...)</li>
          <li>Implement adding labels for account. This allow for an easier organization when using multiple accounts.</li>
          <li>Redesign of our config dialogs to follow the new Plasma System Settings style</li>
          <li>Fix various others issues and small feature requests. Decreasing the total amount of open issues by 20%.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url>https://www.plasma-mobile.org/2022/02/09/plasma-mobile-gear-22-02/#neochat</url>
    </release>
    <release version="21.12" date="2021-12-07">
      <description>
        <p>NeoChat 21.12 brings lots of new features and fixes</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Solved various problems related to login, logout and account switching</li>
          <li>Fixed a few problems in the timeline layout</li>
          <li>Added Spell checking while writing a message</li>
          <li>Improved Settings pages</li>
          <li>Many improvements to the android and general mobile support</li>
          <li>Show blurhashes while images load</li>
          <li>Support showing custom emojis</li>
          <li>Added a global menu</li>
          <li>Added support for spoilers</li>
          <li>Added a quick switcher to switch between rooms</li>
          <li>Added support for an optional fancy blur background effect</li>
          <li>Resizable left and right drawers</li>
          <li>Added Syntax highlighting in raw json messages</li>
          <li>Better wayland support</li>
          <li>Improved file reception and download</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url>https://www.plasma-mobile.org/2021/12/07/plasma-mobile-gear-21-12/</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2021-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>NeoChat 1.2 brings a major redesign of the user interface. The chat page is now using bubbles for the messages and the input component was completely rewritten with a nicer look as well.</p>
        <p>It's now possible to send custom reactions by replying to a comment with /react &lt;message&gt;.</p>
        <p>NeoChat now supports opening Matrix URIs from your browser.</p>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2021/06/01/neochat-1.2/</url>
    </release>
    <release urgency="critical" version="1.1.1" date="2021-02-23"/>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2021-02-22">
      <description>
        <p>Probably the highlight of this release is the completely new login page. It detects the server configuration based on your Matrix Id. This allows you to login to servers requiring Single Sign On (SSO) (like the Mozilla or the incoming Fedora Matrix instance).</p>
        <p>Servers that require agreeing to the TOS before usage are correctly detected now and redirect to their TOS webpage, allowing the user to agree to them instead of silently failing to load the account.</p>
        <p>It is now possible to open a room into a new window. This allows you to view and interact with multiple rooms at the same time.</p>
        <p>We added a few commands to NeoChat (/shrug, /lenny, /join, /ignore, ...).</p>
        <p>We improved the Plasma integration a bit. Now the number of unread messages is displayed in the Plasma Taskbar.</p>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2021/02/22/neochat-1.1/</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2021-01-13">
      <description>
        <p>This version fixes several bugs.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>NeoChat doesn't require a .well-know configuration in the server to work.</li>
          <li>Edited messages won't show up duplicated anymore.</li>
          <li>Various graphic glitches have been fixed.</li>
          <li>NeoChat now ask for consent to terms and conditions if required instead of displaying nothing.</li>
          <li>Users avatar in the room list are now displayed correctly.</li>
          <li>Fix image saving</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2020/01/13/neochat-1.0.1/</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0" date="2020-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of NeoChat, the KDE matrix client.</p>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/23/announcing-neochat-1.0-the-kde-matrix-client/</url>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
