<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  - SPDX-License-Identifier: CC0-1.0
  - SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2020-2021 Carl Schwan <carlschwan@kde.org>
  - SPDX-FileCopyrightText: 2020-2021 Tobias Fella <fella@posteo.de>
 -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.neochat</id>
  <provides>
    <binary>neochat</binary>
  </provides>
  <name>NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="az">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ia">Neochat</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="nn">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="pa">ਨਿਓ-ਚੈਟ</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="ta">நியோச்சாட்</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">NeoChat</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxNeoChatxx</name>
  <summary>A client for matrix, the decentralized communication protocol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="az">Matrix üçün müştəri, mərkəzləşməmiş kommunikasiya protokolu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Un client per al Matrix, el protocol de comunicacions descentralitzat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Un client per al Matrix, el protocol de comunicacions descentralitzat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Klient pro decentralizovaný komunikační protokol matrix</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Ein Programm für Matrix, das dezentrale Kommunikationsprotokoll</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">A client for matrix, the decentralised communication protocol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Un cliente para Matrix, el protocolo de comunicaciones descentralizado</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="eu">Matrix, deszentralizatutako komunikazio protokolorako bezero bat</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Asiakas Matrixille, hajautetulle viestintäyhteyskäytännölle</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Un client pour « Matrix », le protocole décentralisé de communications.</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">Kliens a matrixhoz, a decentralizált kommunikációs protokollhoz</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ia">Un cliente per Matrix, le protocollo de communication decentralisate</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Klien untuk matrix, protokol komunikasi terdesentralisasi</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Un client per matrix, il protocollo di comunicazione decentralizzato</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">Matrix, 분산 대화 프로토콜 클라이언트</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Een client voor matrix, het gedecentraliseerde communicatieprotocol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nn">Ein klient for Matrix, den desentraliserte lynmeldings­protokollen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pa">ਮੈਟਰਿਕਸ, ਸਰਬ-ਸਾਂਝੇ ਸੰਚਾਰ ਪਰੋਟੋਕਾਲ, ਲਈ ਕਲਾਈਂਟ ਹੈ</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Program do obsługi matriksa, rozproszonego protokołu porozumiewania się</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Um cliente para o Matrix, o protocolo de comunicação descentralizado</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Um cliente do Matrix, o protocolo de comunicação descentralizado</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Klient pre matrix, decentralizovaný komunikačný protokol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Odjemalec za matrix, decentralizirani komunikacijski protokol</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">En klient för Matrix, det decentraliserade kommunikationsprotokollet</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Клієнт matrix, децентралізованого протоколу обміну даними</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxA client for matrix, the decentralized communication protocolxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>NeoChat is a Matrix client. It allows you to send text messages, videos and audio files to your family, colleagues and friends using the Matrix protocol.</p>
    <p xml:lang="az">NeoChat Mtrix müştərisidir. O, Matrix protokolundan istifadə edərək, ailənizə, dostlarınıza, iş yoldaşlarınıza mətn, səsli və görüntülü ismarıclar göndərməyə imkan verir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El NeoChat és un client Matrix. Permet enviar missatges de text, fitxers de vídeo i d'àudio a la família, col·legues i amics usant el protocol Matrix.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El NeoChat és un client Matrix. Permet enviar missatges de text, fitxers de vídeo i d'àudio a la família, col·legues i amics usant el protocol Matrix.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">NeoChat ist ein Matrix-Client. Er ermöglicht Ihnen das Senden von Textnachrichten, Videos und Audiodateien an Ihre Familie, Kollegen und Freunde unter Verwendung des Matrix-Protokolls.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">NeoChat es un cliente para Matrix. Le permite enviar mensajes de texto, vídeos y archivos de sonido a su familia, compañeros de trabajo y amigos usando el protocolo Matrix.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">NeoChat은 Matrix 클라이언트입니다. Matrix 프로토콜을 사용하여 가족, 동료, 친구에게 텍스트 메시지, 동영상, 오디오 파일을 전송할 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">NeoChat is een Matrix-client. Het biedt u het verzenden van tekstberichten, video's en geluidsbestanden naar uw familie, collega's en vrienden met het Matrix-protocol.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">NeoChat — клієнт мережі обміну повідомленнями Matrix. За допомогою цієї програми ви зможете надсилати текстові повідомлення, відео та звукові файли вашій родині, колегам та друзям за допомогою протоколу Matrix.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxNeoChat is a Matrix client. It allows you to send text messages, videos and audio files to your family, colleagues and friends using the Matrix protocol.xx</p>
    <p>Matrix is a decentralized communication protocol, putting the user back in control. Currently NeoChat implements large part of the protocol with the exception of encrypted chats and video chat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="az">Matrix, istifadəçini nəzarətdə saxlayan, mərkəzləşməmişi rabitə protokoludur. NeoChat, söhbətin və video əlaqəsinin şifrələnməsindən başqa bir çox protokolları həyata keçirə bilir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Matrix és un protocol de comunicacions descentralitzat, que retorna el control a l'usuari. Actualment el NeoChat implementa una gran part del protocol amb l'excepció dels xats encriptats i els xats de vídeo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El Matrix és un protocol de comunicacions descentralitzat, que retorna el control a l'usuari. Actualment el NeoChat implementa una gran part del protocol amb l'excepció dels xats encriptats i els xats de vídeo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Matrix ist ein dezentralisiertes Kommunikationsprotokoll, das dem Benutzer wieder die Kontrolle zurückgibt. Derzeit implementiert NeoChat einen großen Teil des Protokolls mit der Ausnahme von verschlüsselten Chats und Video-Chat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Matrix es un protocolo de comunicaciones descentralizado, que devuelve el control al usuario. En la actualidad, NeoChat implementa gran parte del protocolo con la excepción de chats cifrados y chats de vídeo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Matrix는 사용자에게 제어권을 돌려 주는 분산 통신 프로토콜입니다. NeoChat은 암호화된 대화 및 영상 통화를 제외한 프로토콜의 대부분 기능을 구현합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Matrix is een gedecentraliseerd communicatieprotocol, dat de gebruiker de controle teruggeeft. Op dit moment implementeert NeoChat grote delen van het protocol met de uitzondering van versleutelde chats en video-chat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Matrix — протокол децентралізованого спілкування, який передає контроль над даними користувачеві. У поточній версії NeoChat реалізовано більшу частину протоколу, окрім зашифрованого спілкування та відеоспілкування.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxMatrix is a decentralized communication protocol, putting the user back in control. Currently NeoChat implements large part of the protocol with the exception of encrypted chats and video chat.xx</p>
    <p>NeoChat works both on mobile and desktop while providing a consistent user experience.</p>
    <p xml:lang="az">Vahid istifadəçi interfeysi ilə təmin olunan NeoChat, həm mobil telefonda həm də kompyuterlərdə işləyir.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El NeoChat funciona en el mòbils i a l'escriptori, proporcionant un experiència d'usuari coherent.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">El NeoChat funciona en el mòbils i a l'escriptori, proporcionant un experiència d'usuari coherent.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">NeoChat funktioniert sowohl auf dem Mobiltelefon als auch auf dem Arbeitsfläche und bietet ein einheitliches Benutzererlebnis. </p>
    <p xml:lang="es">NeoChat funciona en móviles y en el escritorio a la vez que proporciona una experiencia de usuario consistente.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">NeoChat은 모바일과 데스크톱 모두에서 일관된 사용자 경험을 제공합니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">NeoChat werkt zowel op de mobiel en het bureaublad met het leveren van een consistente gebruikerservaring.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">NeoChat працює на мобільних пристроях та звичайних комп'ютерах, маючи однорідний інтерфейс на усіх підтримуваних пристроях.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxNeoChat works both on mobile and desktop while providing a consistent user experience.xx</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">https://apps.kde.org/neochat/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://invent.kde.org/network/neochat/-/issues</url>
  <categories>
    <category>Network</category>
  </categories>
  <developer_name>The KDE Community</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="az">KDE Cəmiyyəti</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ca">La comunitat KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ca-valencia">La comunitat KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="cs">Komunita KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="de">Die KDE-Gemeinschaft</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="en-GB">The KDE Community</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="es">La comunidad KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="eu">KDE komunitatea</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fi">KDE-yhteisö</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="fr">La communauté de KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="hu">A KDE Közösség</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ia">Le communitate de KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="id">Komunitas KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="it">La comunità KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="ko">KDE 커뮤니티</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="nl">De KDE gemeenschap</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="nn">KDE-fellesskapet</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pa">ਕੇਡੀਈ ਕਮਿਊਨਟੀ</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pl">Społeczność KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pt">A Comunidade do KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="pt-BR">A comunidade KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sk">KDE Komunita</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sl">Skupnost KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="sv">KDE-gemenskapen</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="uk">Спільнота KDE</developer_name>
  <developer_name xml:lang="x-test">xxThe KDE Communityxx</developer_name>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0</project_license>
  <value key="KDE::matrix">#neochat:kde.org</value>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/neochat/application-mobile.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cdn.kde.org/screenshots/neochat/application.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">intense</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2021-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>NeoChat 1.2 brings a major redesign of the user interface. The chat page is now using bubbles for the messages and the input component was completely rewritten with a nicer look as well.</p>
        <p>It's now possible to send custom reactions by replying to a comment with /react &lt;message&gt;.</p>
        <p>NeoChat now supports opening Matrix URIs from your browser.</p>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2021/06/01/neochat-1.2/</url>
    </release>
    <release urgency="critical" version="1.1.1" date="2021-02-23"/>
    <release version="1.1.0" date="2021-02-22">
      <description>
        <p>Probably the highlight of this release is the completely new login page. It detects the server configuration based on your Matrix Id. This allows you to login to servers requiring Single Sign On (SSO) (like the Mozilla or the incoming Fedora Matrix instance).</p>
        <p>Servers that require agreeing to the TOS before usage are correctly detected now and redirect to their TOS webpage, allowing the user to agree to them instead of silently failing to load the account.</p>
        <p>It is now possible to open a room into a new window. This allows you to view and interact with multiple rooms at the same time.</p>
        <p>We added a few commands to NeoChat (/shrug, /lenny, /join, /ignore, ...).</p>
        <p>We improved the Plasma integration a bit. Now the number of unread messages is displayed in the Plasma Taskbar.</p>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2021/02/22/neochat-1.1/</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2021-01-13">
      <description>
        <p>This version fixes several bugs.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>NeoChat doesn't require a .well-know configuration in the server to work.</li>
          <li>Edited messages won't show up duplicated anymore.</li>
          <li>Various graphic glitches have been fixed.</li>
          <li>NeoChat now ask for consent to terms and conditions if required instead of displaying nothing.</li>
          <li>Users avatar in the room list are now displayed correctly.</li>
          <li>Fix image saving</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2020/01/13/neochat-1.0.1/</url>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0" date="2020-12-23">
      <description>
        <p>Initial release of NeoChat, the KDE matrix client.</p>
      </description>
      <url>https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/23/announcing-neochat-1.0-the-kde-matrix-client/</url>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
